VIJAYAKUMAR MURUGAN

2, Chelliamman Kovil Street,

Thirukazhukundram. Chennai. India.

Email: vijayakmurugan@gmail.com

Mob No: +91 - 9994085166 / +968 - 7933 1855

Passport no: L6096821

Objective:

To obtain the excellence profession, development and expansion in career and to be associated with apparent and successful company to seek a challenging position to expand my skills and quality of my profession to the fullest of my ability.

Professional Summary:

Competent and versatile Material Management Professional with rich and varied exposure of over 11 years to the entire spectrum of Material Management, Logistics Management, Warehouse operations, Production and General Administration. Strong Team leader, builder and facilitator, fostering an atmosphere that motivates highly talented professionals to balance high-level skills with maximum productivity. Equipped with the knowledge of utilizing surplus materials to the maximum that generates good revenue for the company.

Skills:

➤ SAP MUSTAQBAL R/3 Production (P68)

➤ Packages: MS-Office, Excel & Computer Networking

Operating System: Windows XP, 7 & 8

> Application: Auto CAD & Pro - E

➤ Inventory Management

➤ Lean Operations

> 5s Implementation

Professional Experience:

M/s. Al Turki Enterprises L.L.C., Muscat, Oman August 2015 – till now

(Product: On-Plot Delivery Contractor for PDO O&G)

Designation - Senior Engineer - Logistics, Material & Equipment Planning.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- > Co-ordinate with client warehouse & 4PL logistics team for the timely delivery of material and equipment based on priorities.
- > Co-ordinate with site materials controller and construction department or contractors to resolve equipment & materials issue in consultation with project engineer.
- > To reconcile materials for the completed projects with the contractor (through interior materials controller).
- > Coordinate with project engineers, design consultant and procurement department to ensure timely availability of equipment & materials.



- > Setting up the ware housing internal procedure to ensure a strong level of control, smooth flow of operation and continuous support and coordination regarding all project requirements.
- > To oversee and control material movements at the central ware house includes receipt, checking, and efficient storage of stock items and issue of the materials.
- > Ensuring material control activities including site purchasing, expediting, receipt, inspection, quality assurance, and storage are in compliance with project procedures.
- > Coordinate material requirements between site, contractors and Client to ensure compliance to plan.
- > Implement and monitors systems which ensure that only suitable and approved materials are issued for use in the work; material is adequately stored, marked and maintained.
- > Preparing the overage, shortage and damaged (OS&D) reports and reporting to the head office procurement department.
- > Establish procedures for standardization and control of materials, equipment, parts and supplies for construction operations.
- > Communications and coordinates with HO procurement department and vendors to resolve any problems and shipment discrepancies.
- > Decide whether the arriving cargo is to be loaded at site storage area, remote storage area or directly to the construction site under coordination with concern section under coordination with other material controllers.
- > Extensive experience in handling of Piping Material Metallic and Non-Metallic pipes and piping components such as Elbows Tees, Reducers, Flanges, Valves, Gasket, Stud Bolts/Nuts of various types of metal like MS, CS, SS, CI, GI, various Alloy and Copper etc.
- > Monitors controls and forecasts piping commodity materials and ensures piping materials are listed and requisitioned to meet project requirements and Co-ordination with the Procurement.
- > Prepare MATERIAL INSPECTION REPORT (MIR) or REQUEST FOR INSPECTION (RFI) once the arrived material becomes ready for inspection.
- > Participate in HSE, Internal & external audits as directed by Project Managers & QA/QC team as per PDO Quality System Procedure (QSP).
- > Physically conduct periodic stock taking on all categories of materials held at warehouses / yards and update their inventory records accordingly.
- Responsible to maintain and arrange all materials control related documents received from respective subcontractor like MSDS (MATERIAL SAFETY DATA SHEET) & MTC (MATERIAL TEST CERTIFICATE).
- > Comply HSE policies at all levels and Maintain / Control housekeeping in the warehouse and yard to ensure materials are stored in an organized manner creating a safe working environment as per Safety procedures.
- > Coordinate materials and handling resources, record all material and utilize of a computerized inventory management system (SAP R3).

Piping Standards:

- Conversant with ASME B31.3 & ASME B31.1 and other ASME, API, ASTM, NACE, MSS, BS and IS Codes & standards relating to design / material specification of piping engineering and other industrial Standards Practices.
- Valves & Valve Material Specifications: Comprehensive knowledge of gate, globe, check, ball, butterfly & other special valves- Preparing valve specifications/ datasheets; review in valve GA drawings from vendors.
- Metallic/ Non-metallic Piping: In addition to the customary metallic piping (CS, SS, AS), have experience with non-metallic piping systems such as RTR (GRE, GRP).
- Vendor Drawing Review: Reviews Vendor Drawings for bulk items like valves and various specialty items like strainers, steam traps, sample coolers, safety showers etc.

Scope of the work in SAP:

- Creating NW / PR for Bulk procurement
- Goods Issue Entry / Goods Receipts Entry
- Stock Transfer Order (STO) Creation
- ➤ Preparing MTS with Purchase Order (PO)/ Work Order (WO)/Network.
- > To run various types of reports related to transactions of material, outstanding PR/PO's Stock etc.

Previous Experience:

1. M/s. FLOWSERVE SANMAR LIMITED March 2012–June 2015

Karapakkam, Chennai. (Product: Industrial Valves & Mechanical Seal) Designation – Assistant Engineer (Purchase & Inventory Control)

2. AUDCO INDIA LIMITEDMay 2011 – February 2012

Maraimalai Nagar, Chennai. (Product: Industrial VALVES) Junior Engineer - Purchase

3. TVS Sundaram Fasteners Limited

April 2010 - May 2011

Mahindra city, Chennai. (Product: HUB, SPRACKET, SHAFT for passenger car) Trainee – Production

EDUCATION:

- Diploma in Mechanical Engineering 2008-2010 from Arulmigu Thirupurasundari Amman Polytechnic, Thirukazhukundram.
- 12thin 2008 from Sri Ramakrishna Mission from Chengalpattu.
- 10th in 2006 from PTVS High School from Thirukazhukundram.

DECLARATION:

I hereby acknowledge that all the above furnished details and information's are true to the best of my knowledge.

Station: Chennai, India

Date : (VIJAYAKUMAR MURUGAN)